Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Economics and Contracts Department records 1955-2012 IBT0021
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Economics and Contracts Department Records
1955-2012
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
IBT0021
4.5 Linear Feet
This collection is comprised of agreements and contracts of local unions of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters various dating from 1955 to 2012.
Biographical / Historical
The Economics and Contracts Department serves the local affiliates and Teamsters Trade Divisions/Conferences as a source of financial, statistical and agreements information. The department provides local affiliates and International Union personnel with corporate research and economic trends for use in both collective bargaining and organizing.
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of agreements and contracts of local unions of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters various dating from 1955 to 2012.
Arrangement
Organized into one series: Contracts and Agreements.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 2009 [2009.092].
Contracts; Labor unions; Labor; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century
- Contracts and Agreements, 1955-2012; Series 1; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America; 4 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  Arranged in ascending order by union number, followed by multi-union contracts.
  Labor; Contracts; Labor unions
  - Local Union 2 OPEIU Collective Bargaining Agreement, July 1, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Local Union 2 OPEIU Agreement Summary Sheets, July 2011 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Local Union 2 OPEIU Agreement Summary Sheets, May - July 2012 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Local Unions 2,6,25, 1975-2011; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Local Unions 52,67,70,81,117, 1955-2013; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Local Union 117, 2004-2012; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Local Unions 133,135,137, 1962-2011; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Local Union 205, 2007-2010; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Local Union 205, 2007-2010; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Local Unions 211,238,320, 1952-2008; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Local Unions 312,320, 2006-2009; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Local Union 320, 2005-2009; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Local Union 320, 2006-2009; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Local Union 320, 1993-2009; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Local Unions 322,331, 1996-2009; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Local Unions 337,339,397,414, 2004-2010; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Local Unions 414,453,456,481, 1992-2012; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Local Union 486, 1998-2010; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Local Union 486, 2004-2009; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Local Unions 495,500,509,533,542,550, 2000-2011; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Local Unions 564,572,578,592,598, 1991-2008; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Local Unions 601,631,673,682,688, 1960-2010; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Local Union 693, 2006-2011; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Local Union 695, 2006-2011; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Local Union 695, 2005-2011; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Local Union 695, 2005-2011; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Local Union 695, 2005-2011; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Local Unions 697,705,707,710,728, 1991-2011; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Local Unions 730,734,743,748,760,769,773,767,781, 1970-2011; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Local Unions 808,830, 2000-2012; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Local Unions 879,880,886,896, 1992-2009; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Local Unions 901,911, 1995-2011; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Local Unions 929,948, 1993-2010; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Local Unions 952,357,959, 1996-2010; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Local Unions 974,986, 1989-2010; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Local Unions 997,1205,1620, 2003-2011; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Local Unions 1070 & 1688 Collective Agreements, October 1998 - September 2001 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Multi-Union Contracts, 1991-2011; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Multi-Union Contracts, 1991-2011; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Central States Area Local Cartage Agreements Supplements, 1955-1964 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Central States Area Local Cartage Agreements Supplements, 1964-1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Central States Area Local Cartage Agreements Supplements, 1970-1976 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Central States Area Local Cartage Agreements Supplements, 1982-1988 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Central States Area Local Cartage Agreements Supplements, 1988-1994 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - National Motor Freight Agreement Central States Over the Road Supplemental Agreements, 1952-1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - National Motor Freight Agreement Central States Over the Road Supplemental Agreements, 1964-1970 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - National Motor Freight Agreement Central States Over the Road Supplemental Agreements, 1970-1979 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - National Motor Freight Agreement Central States Over the Road Supplemental Agreements, 1979-1994 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Central States Tank Truck Agreements, 1961-1964 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Central States Tank Truck Agreements, 1964-1970 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Central States Tank Truck Agreements, 1970-1979 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Central States Tank Truck Agreements, 1982-1991 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - National Master Automobile Transporters Agreement and Central Conference Supplemental Agreements, 1964-1970 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - National Master Automobile Transporters Agreement and Central Conference Supplemental Agreements, 1964-1970 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - National Master Automobile Transporters Agreement and Central Conference Supplemental Agreements, 1985-1991 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Central States Area Master Dairy Agreements, 1964-1974 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Western States Area Private, Common, and Contract Carriers Supplemental Agreements, 1961-1964 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Western States Area Private, Common, and Contract Carriers Supplemental Agreements, 1961-1964 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - National Master Freight Agreement Over the Road, 1994-1998 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Automobile Carrier Truckaway Agreement, 1952-1964 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Western States Master Freight Agreements, 1961-1967 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - National Master Freight Agreement and National Iron and Steel and Special Commodity Supplemental Agreements, 1964-1967 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Truck Tank Agreements Michigan and North and South Dakota Rider, 1967-1979 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Central States Over the Road Motor Freight Agreements, 1955-1961 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Highway, Railroad, and Heavy Construction Minnesota Agreements, 1962-1971 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Master Cement and All Dry Commodities Agreements, 1970-1982 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous Working Agreements, 1946-1954 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous Working Agreements, 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Procedural Rules and Regulations of National Joint Board for Settlement of Jurisdictional Disputes Building and Construction Industry, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Working Agreements, 1960-1966 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous Working Agreements, 1964-1971 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Working Agreements, 1971-1981 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Automobile Carrier City Delivery, Pull-out, Mounting Service, Yard and Garage Agreements, 1955-1964 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Fairmont Foods Company Master Agreements Central-Southern Conference, 1966-1976 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Silverline, Inc Agreements, 1971-1981 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Minneapolis Automobil Dealer's Association Working Agreements, 1971-1977 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - National Master Freight Agreement State Supplements Contract Guide, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Alma Plastics Company Agreement, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Armor Country Trucking Agreement Central and Southern Conference, 1970-1979 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - SF Kennedy New Products and IBT Local 279 Agreement, 1973-1979 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous Working Agreements, 1942-1948 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous Working Agreements, 1951-1953 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous Working Agreements, 1955-1961 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Southern Conference Over the Road Agreement Guide, 1982-1985 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - National Master Freight Agreement Annotated Guide and Supplements, 1976-1984 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Current Economic Data for Collective Bargaining Fact Sheet, 150 Tractor Trailer Drivers Area Work Survey, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - National Master Freight Agreement and Western States Area Supplemental Agreement; Over-the-Road, Pick-Up and Delivery Local Cartage and Dock Workers, July 1964 - March 1967 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Joint Council No. 42 - Team Roster, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - National Master Freight Agreement - Western States, April 1970 - June 1973 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Agreement Local No. 404, 1910-1919; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Contract between The Colorado Herald Publishing Co. and the Denver Newspaper Pressmen's Union No. 22, June 12, 1939; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Armor Country Trucking Agreement, 1973-1976; Series 3 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Highway Truck Drivers and Helpers Local 107 National Master Freight Agreement, July 20, 1964; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Liquor Salesmen's Agreement with Wholesale Delivery Drivers & Salesmen's Union Locals 848,953 Constitution and By-Laws of Construction, Building Material - :Local Union No. 682, 1968-1971; Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Alliedsignal and United Steelworkers Agreement, 1996; IBT0021 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Bell Atlantic and Communication Workers of America General Agreement, 1996; IBT0021 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - National Master UPS Agreement with IBT, 1997; IBT0021 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Oil, Chemical, Atomic Workers Agreement, 1996; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Oil, Chemical, Atomic Workers Agreement, 1997; IBT0021 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Pacific Coast Longshore Contract, 1999; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Wayne County Michigan Agreement with ALF-CIO, 1976; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - United Auto Works and Ford Motor Agreement, 1990; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Baltimore Teachers Union Agreement, 2001; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Dade County Public Schools Contract, 1994; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Dade County Public Schools Contract, 1985; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Northwest Airlines and International Association of Machinists Agreement, 1993; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Pratt Whitney and AFL-CIO Agreement, 1998; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Pepco Agreement with International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 1900, 1993; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Steamfitters Union Agreement, D.C., 1987; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - United Steelworkers of America, Local 90 Agreement, 1997; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - United Airlines Agreement, 2003; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - UAW and General Motors Agreement, 1984; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - UAW and General Motors Agreement, 1993; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - UAW and Ford Letter of Understanding, 1990; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - UAW and Ford Agreement, 2003; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - UFCW Local 400 Collective Bargaining Agreements, 1996-2008; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - UPS and AFLCIO Agreements, 1994; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - UPS and AFLCIO Agreement, 1998; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - United University Professions and the State of New York Agreement, 1991; IBT 0021 Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 4)